## Marat Saytakov · iOS Software Engineer · Résumé · CV

#### Introduction

My name is Marat Saytakov. I am iOS software engineer, 4+ years iOS development experience. I do like Swift. And respect Objective-C.

Graduated Moscow State University, studied computer science and microchip programming. Have an Engineer's degree in Information Systems.

Live in Moscow, Russia. Ready to relocate.

Skills Contact

Objective-C and Swift. 99% crash-free apps. Email: <u>m.saytakov@yandex.ru</u>

Smooth UI maker. Web: <u>m4rr.ru</u>

Short-list: iOS SDK, Cocoa Touch, ARC, GCD, GitHub: m4rr

Xcode, design patterns, CocoaPods, Crashlytics, LinkedIn: maratsaytakov

Git, JSON, REST, Apple HIG.

Languages: Russian (native), English (fluent).

#### Contribution

Apple **Swift contributor** on GitHub · 2016 github.com/apple/swift

Codementor · 2015—Present

I am a code mentor, covering expertise of Swift, plain C, Objective-C and Xcode. codementor.io/m4rr

Moscow Coding School · 2015—Present

Mentoring students at offline Swift Programming course.

moscoding.ru/ios

CocoaHeads Moscow · 2013—Present

Active member of Moscow iOS/OS X developers community.

Given talks: Size Classes (2014, in Russian)

### **Education**

**Engineer's degree** in Information Systems at Faculty of Cybernetics in Moscow State University of Radio-engineering, Electronics and Automation (<u>H+ for MIREA</u>) September 2007—July 2012

## **Employment**

Freelance iOS developer · 2015—Present

Tested Upwork member. Top 30% in iOS Programming Test; Top 20% in Swift Test.

**Luuk** · <u>luuk.com</u> · October 2014—Sep. 2015 · Lead iOS Developer Luuk is most famous beauty-industry startup in Moscow. I released both of current apps. Achievements: 99% crash-free app, 30k users in first month. Using Swift code in production.

**RocketBank** · <u>rocketbank.ru</u> · Sep. 2013—Sep. 2014 · iOS Developer In the team of two developers took a part of development the second version of RocketBank. Meanwhile I released a RocketBank-based MVP of card-to-card mobile application — <u>rocketka.ru</u>.

**Aic** · <u>aic.ru</u> · August 2012—August 2013 · iOS Developer Prototyping a mobile app of future banking concept: <u>Money Inc</u>. Is the simple app to manage one's own banking accounts.

# **Side Projects**

Chars · chars.cc · App Store

Beautiful and native way to type everything with Unicode characters on iOS.

Easy Percent · App Store

Much easier and pretty nice calculator of taxes and reversed percent.

Sochi Safety Guide · Ocloudesign · App Store

A Guide about one's safety in Russia.